Welcome. In the last lecture, we created two callback functions that will be triggered
欢迎。在上一节课中，我们创建了两个将被触发的回调函数
when our player enters and exits the clamp state. And in this lecture, we are going to
当我们的玩家进入和退出夹具状态时。在这堂课中，我们将介绍
look at how we can use these two functions to add in and remove input mapping context.
看看我们如何使用这两个函数来添加和删除输入映射上下文。
So this is the default mapping context that we've been using. And you can see inside of
这是我们一直使用的默认映射上下文。你可以看到里面的
it there are four actions. So we have jump, move, look, and our clamp. So for this move,
它有四个动作。所以我们有跳跃，移动，看和我们的钳子。因此，对于这一举动，
you can see these are the key bindings and we can use these keys to move our character
您可以看到这些键绑定，我们可以使用这些键来移动我们的角色
on the ground. And what I want here is I like to also use these same keys to move our character
趴在地上。我想要的是我也想用这些键来移动我们的角色
when we are climbing. And I also don't want to check the clamp state at the input level.
当我们在爬山的时候。我也不想检查输入电平上的钳位状态。
So how can we do that? Well, to achieve what we want, we'll need to understand how to use
那么我们怎么才能做到这一点呢？好的，为了实现我们想要的，我们需要了解如何使用
this mapping context. So our default move action is inside of this default input mapping
此映射上下文。因此，我们的默认移动操作位于此默认输入映射的内部
context. And in order for this to work, we'll need to create a new input action. Here I'm
背景。为了使其起作用，我们需要创建一个新的输入操作。我在这里
going to call it climb move action. And this action here, it needs to be in its own input
我要把它叫做攀爬移动行动。而这个动作，它需要在自己的输入中
mapping context. So I'm going to call it climb input mapping context. And this move action
映射上下文。因此，我将其称为爬升输入映射上下文。而这一移动动作
will have the exact same key binding as this default move action. So somehow we'll need
将具有与此默认移动操作完全相同的键绑定。所以不知何故我们需要
to allow this action to override this one. And thanks to our enhanced input system to
以允许此操作覆盖此操作。多亏了我们增强的输入系统
do that, we just need to change their priority. So this default input mapping context will
要做到这一点，我们只需要改变他们的优先顺序。因此，此默认输入映射上下文将
be added at priority zero. And if we want to override this action, this newly added mapping
被添加到优先级为零。如果我们想要覆盖此操作，则新添加的映射
context needs to be a higher priority. So I'm going to say priority one. As long as the
背景需要是更高的优先级。所以我要说的是第一要务。只要
number here is higher than this one, even though these two actions, they have the same
这里的数字比这个高，即使这两个动作，它们有相同的
key binding, the higher one will override the lower one. So that's the theory part.
键绑定，较高的键绑定将覆盖较低的键绑定。这就是理论上的部分。
Let's start coding. I'm going to close my project, go back to my visual studio. I'm
让我们开始编码吧。我要结束我的项目，回到我的视觉工作室。我
going to go inside of this climbing system character.h. Then I'm going to copy this mapping
要进入这个攀爬系统的角色。然后我要复制这张地图
context and I'm going to paste it in here. And this time I'm going to call it climb mapping
上下文，我将把它粘贴到这里。这一次我要把它叫做攀登地图
context. Then above these two mapping context, I'm going to create two handy functions to
背景。然后，在这两个映射上下文之上，我将创建两个方便的函数来
add and remove the mapping context we want. So under these two callback functions, I'm
添加和删除所需的映射上下文。因此，在这两个回调函数下，我
going to create the first one. I'm going to call it add input mapping context, and it's
我要创建第一个。我将其称为添加输入映射上下文，它是
going to have two function inputs. So the first one is going to be this u input mapping context.
将有两个功能输入。所以第一个将是这个u输入映射上下文。
I'm going to call it context to add. And the second one is going to be in 32. I'm going
我将把它称为上下文来添加。而第二个将在32岁。我要走了
to call it in priority. All right. That's the first function. And the second function,
将其列为优先事项。好的。这是第一个函数。以及第二个功能，
I'm going to call it remove input mapping context. And the rest is going to be the same as this
我将其称为删除输入映射上下文。其余部分将与此相同
function. But this time we don't need this priority. All right, I'm going to create two
功能。但这一次，我们不需要这个优先事项。好的，我要创建两个
function definitions, place this function under begin play. So paste it in here. Then
函数定义，将此函数放在Begin Play下。所以把它贴在这里。然后
create a function definition for removing input mapping context. So paste the function
创建用于删除输入映射上下文的函数定义。因此，粘贴该函数
definition in here. So the function body for adding, we have the exact code we need.
定义在这里。所以要添加的函数体，我们有了我们需要的确切代码。
So it's inside of the speaking plane. These lines come with this template code that we
所以它在说话的飞机里。这些行与我们的模板代码一起提供
are using. So I'm going to cut these lines and paste them in here. So first we need to
都在使用。所以我要把这些线条剪下来，粘贴到这里。所以首先我们需要
cast to get hold of our player controller. Then we'll need to access this enhanced input
施法来控制我们的玩家控制器。那么我们就需要访问这个增强的输入
subsystem. Once this subsystem is valid, we can add mapping context. So now this time,
子系统。一旦这个子系统有效，我们就可以添加映射上下文。所以这一次，
instead of adding this default mapping context, I'm going to change this to context to add.
我不会添加这个默认的映射上下文，而是将其更改为要添加的上下文。
So our function input and change the priority to be this in priority. All right, that's
因此，我们的函数输入并将优先级更改为该优先级。好的，这就是
the adding and I'm going to copy this code again. I'm going to take care of removing.
加法后，我将再次复制这段代码。我会负责搬走的。
So this time we need to call a different function. It's called remove mapping context. And I'm
所以这一次我们需要调用一个不同的函数。这称为删除映射上下文。而且我是
going to pass in this context to add. So that's adding and removing done. And just to be safe
将在此上下文中传递以添加。因此，添加和删除操作已经完成。为了安全起见
here, I'm also going to check if this mapping context is valid. If it's not valid, I'm going
在这里，我还将检查该映射上下文是否有效。如果无效，我就去
to return and do the same thing for this removing. And next thing I'm going to call this function
返回并为这个移除做同样的事情。接下来，我将调用这个函数
inside of begin play. So here we need to add in the default mapping context and the default
在Begin Play内部。因此，在这里，我们需要添加默认映射上下文和默认
priority will be zero. So that's the basics app. I'm going to try to compile first. All
优先级将为零。这就是基本的应用程序。我要先试着编译。全
right, I have a successful compile and next thing I'm going to call this function. So
好的，我已经成功编译了，接下来我要调用这个函数。所以
copy it and go down to this on player enter climb state. I'm going to paste the function
复制它并在玩家进入爬升状态时向下移动。我要粘贴该函数
in here and this time I'm going to add in this client mapping context. The priority
在这里，这一次我将添加这个客户端映射上下文。优先事项
I'm going to set it to be one. So when we're climbing, we'll only be using input call back
我要将其设置为1。因此，当我们攀登时，我们将只使用输入回调
functions that are only built for climbing. All right, this is the adding and when we
仅为攀登而建的功能。好的，这是加法，当我们
exit the climb state, I'm going to call the function remove mapping context and pass in
退出攀登状态，我将调用函数Remove映射上下文并传入
this climb mapping context. And that's our client mapping context done. And next thing
这一攀登地图的背景。这就是我们的客户端映射上下文。下一件事是
we need to take care of the input action. So go back to my header file. I'm going to
我们需要处理输入操作。因此，返回到我的头文件。我这就做
scroll down. I'm going to copy this move action, paste it in here. I'm going to change it to
向下滚动。我要复制这个移动动作，粘贴到这里。我要把它改成
climb move action. Then I'm going to go back to my CPP file, scroll up to the function
爬升移动动作。然后，我将返回到我的CPP文件，向上滚动到函数
mining for this input component. Then I'm going to copy this by action move action.
挖掘此输入组件。然后我将通过动作移动动作来复制它。
I'm going to copy it and paste it in here. So instead of move action, I'm going to change
我要把它复制并粘贴到这里。所以我要改变的不是行动，而是改变
this to climb move action and the trigger event will be triggered. One interesting thing
该爬升移动动作和触发事件将被触发。一件有趣的事
here to mention is you can see for this jump action, the trigger event is triggered as
值得一提的是，您可以看到，对于此跳转操作，触发事件被触发为
well. So that means if we hold down our space bar the whole time, our player will keep jumping.
井。这意味着如果我们一直按住空格键，我们的球员就会继续跳跃。
I don't think that should be the case for jumping. Instead of this triggered, I think
我认为这不应该是跳跃的情况。而不是触发，我认为
it should be this started. But again, this one here passed the Apex code review, so it
应该是从这个开始的。但是再一次，这里的这个通过了Apex代码审查，所以它
must be here for a reason. All right, I'm going to scroll to the right. So for this
一定是有原因的。好的，我要向右滚动。所以为了这件事
default move action, now we don't need to bind it to this move. We can just bind it
默认移动操作，现在我们不需要将其绑定到此移动。我们可以把它绑在一起
to the function that we created. So it's called handle ground movement input. And for this
添加到我们创建的函数。所以它被称为手柄地面运动输入。为了这一点
climb move action, I'm going to bind it to the function for climb movement. So it's called
爬升移动动作，我要将它绑定到爬升移动的功能上。所以它被称为
handle climb movement input. So when we're climbing, this function here will be called.
手柄爬升动作输入。所以当我们攀登的时候，这里的这个函数会被调用。
And when we are walking, this function here will be called. And now we don't need the
当我们行走时，这里的这个函数将被调用。现在我们不需要
default move function anymore. So we don't check this logic here at the input level anymore.
默认的移动功能已经不存在了。所以我们不再在输入级别检查这个逻辑。
I'm going to delete this function, go back to the header file. I'm going to find this
我要删除这个函数，回到头文件。我要去找这个
move and I'm going to delete it and go back to the CPP file. I'm going to delete this
移动，我要删除它，并返回到CPP文件。我要删除这篇文章
one as well. All right, I'm going to try to compile again. I have a successful compile.
再来一杯。好的，我要试着再编译一遍。我有一个成功的汇编。
I'm going to launch my editor back. There are still a couple of things that we need
我要让我的编辑回来。我们还需要几样东西
to do in order for this to work. So first I'm going to organize my folder. I'm going
才能让这件事奏效。所以首先我要整理我的文件夹。我要走了
to move this plane space to this animation folder, select move here and move this control
要将此平面空间移动到此动画文件夹，请选择移动到此处并移动此控件
rake to this folder as well. Then I'm going to directly move this input folder to our
也可以搜索到这个文件夹。然后，我将直接将此输入文件夹移动到我们的
climb system. Inside of that, you can see this is the default mapping context. I'm going
爬升系统。在其中，您可以看到这是默认的映射上下文。我要走了
to move the entire folder over. So drag it to climb system, select move here, then double
要移动整个文件夹，请执行以下操作。因此，拖动它以攀登系统，选择移动到这里，然后双倍
click to open it. Now we can create a new mapping context from scratch and manually
单击以打开它。现在，我们可以从头开始手动创建新的映射上下文
add in those modifiers for move action if we want. And that's just time consuming. The
如果我们需要的话，可以添加移动动作的修饰符。而这是非常耗时的。这个
fastest way to handle it in here will be directly duplicating this mapping context. So I'm going
在这里处理它的最快方法是直接复制该映射上下文。所以我要走了
to select it, press control plus D to duplicate it. I'm going to call this IMC underscore
要选择它，请按Ctrl+D复制它。我将把它称为IMC下划线
climb and double click to open it. So for this climb mapping context, we don't need
爬上去，然后双击打开它。因此，对于这个攀登地图环境，我们不需要
jump. I'm going to delete this. We don't need look. We don't need climb. So I only
跳。我要删除这篇文章。我们不需要看。我们不需要爬。所以我只是
want to keep this IA move and you can see these are the default key bindings. So we'll
我想保持此IA移动，您可以看到这些是默认的密钥绑定。所以我们会
need to create a new input action in here. I'm going to go to actions and I'm going to
需要在此处创建新的输入操作。我要去看比赛，我要去
select this IA move control plus D to duplicate it. I'm going to change this to IA underscore
选择此IA移动控件加D以复制它。我要将其更改为IA下划线
climb move. If you decided to create one from scratch, make sure you set the value type
爬上去，动起来。如果您决定从头开始创建，请确保设置了值类型
for your climb move to be access to D. So if this one here is a digital bull, it just
让你的攀登移动到D，所以如果这是一个数字公牛，它只是
won't work. So keep that in mind. All right. Go back to my client mapping context. I'm
没用的。因此，请记住这一点。好的。返回到我的客户端映射上下文。我
going to change this input action from IA move to IA underscore climb move and hit save.
将此输入操作从IA Move更改为IA下划线，然后攀登、移动并点击保存。
So you can see this newly created input action has the exact same key bindings as a ground
因此，您可以看到这个新创建的输入操作具有与GROUND完全相同的键绑定
movement. And later when we add this mapping context, it will overwrite the one that has
有动静。稍后，当我们添加此映射上下文时，它将覆盖具有
lower priority. All right. There's one last thing that we need to do. So go back to this
优先级较低。好的。我们还需要做最后一件事。所以回到这个问题上
character blueprint, double click to open it. And inside of the search box here, I'm going
人物蓝图，双击即可打开。在这里的搜索框里，我要
to search input. So here we need to add in this climb mapping context. There will be
以搜索输入。所以在这里，我们需要添加这个攀登地图的上下文。会有
our IMC climb and this climb move action. I'm going to add in this IA climb move. All
我们的IMC攀登和这次攀登移动动作。我要加上这个IA攀登动作。全
right. Click compile. I'm going to test this. So press play and we can still move on the
正确的。单击编译。我要测试一下这个。所以按下Play，我们仍然可以继续
ground. I'm going to enter the climb state and I can still climb using the same key.
地面。我要进入攀爬状态，我仍然可以用同样的钥匙攀登。
Only this time we are no longer checking the logic at the input level and we are using
只是这一次我们不再在输入级检查逻辑，而是使用
the newly created mapping context that we just set. Great. This is working as expected.
我们刚刚设置的新创建的映射上下文。太棒了。这起到了预期的作用。
All right. Let's do a quick wrap up. In order for this to work, you'll first need to create
好的。让我们快点结束吧。要使其发挥作用，您首先需要创建
the function for adding and removing mapping context from code. And then we can use these
用于在代码中添加和删除映射上下文的函数。然后我们就可以用这些
functions to help us to do so when the player enters and leaves the climb state. After this
当玩家进入和离开攀爬状态时，帮助我们这样做的函数。在这之后
one, don't forget to bind function to its own input action. So you'll be ground movement
第一，不要忘记将函数绑定到它自己的输入操作。所以你将会是地面运动
to ground movement input action, climb movement to climb movement input action. And inside
到地面动作输入动作，到爬升动作到爬升动作输入动作。在里面
of the editor, don't forget to create the new mapping context and new input action.
在编辑器中，不要忘记创建新的映射上下文和新的输入操作。
And the last step, don't forget to assign the ones that you created in blueprint. And now
最后一步，不要忘记分配您在BluePrint中创建的那些。而现在
with this newly created climb mapping context, we can achieve the two key input actions that
有了这个新创建的攀登映射上下文，我们可以实现以下两个关键输入操作
we want and we'll look at how we can do that in the next lecture. So it's time for you
我们希望，我们将在下一节课中研究如何做到这一点。所以现在是你的时间了
to do the same and refer back to the video if you need help. And I'll see you in the
来做同样的事情，如果你需要帮助，请回过头来看视频。我会在房间里见你
next lecture.
下一堂课。
[MUSIC]
[音乐]
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[BLACK_AUDIO]